Guide to the Stanford University, Women's Physical Education Department, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Women's Physical Education Department, records
1928-1982
SC0144
Stanford University. Women's Physical Education Department.
30 Linear feet (36 boxes)
Records of the department include staff meeting minutes, newsletters, correspondence, materials relating to medical research projects of the faculty, and records of the operation of the Women's Student Health Service. Also includes course materials, correspondence, reports, memoranda, photographs, and miscellaneous materials pertaining to the department and photographs and records of two dance clubs - the Stanford Hoedowners and the Stanford Folk Dancers. Of note are completed survey forms on the recreational needs of women college students, 1948, from Mills College, Stanford, University of New Mexico, and University of Wyoming, with related correspondence and notes.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, Department of Athletics, Physical Education and Recreation, 1975, 1982; gift, Luell Guthrie, 1982.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical note
ADMINISTRATIVE HISTORY OF PHYSICAL EDUCATION FOR WOMEN AT STANFORD 1891-1975
Stanford University had a department of "Physical Training and Personal Hygiene" with facilities for both men and women when it opened in 1891. In 1928-29, the first year represented in this collection, the School of Hygiene and Physical Education was divided into four areas: Informational Hygiene; Physcical Education, including athletics; Student Health Service; University Health Service. The Men's and Women's Student Health Services administered annual examinations for all students, provided a referral service for students who were ill, and, with the help of a mother's group, provided a Rest Home for mildly ill students. The University Health Service examined food handlers in the University food services, analyzed samples of the university water and milk supply, etc.
In 1929-30 the new Roble gymnasium for women was constructed. The functions and positions of Medical Advisor of Women and Director of Physical Education for Women were combined under one unified Department of Hygiene and Physical Education for Women. The director and her assistants examined each student annually. Based on the resulting report, a physical fitness program appropriate to the health of each student was prescribed. Women who missed Physical Education classes, or who were performing inadequately in their academic work, were required to report to the director. The women's department offered courses in gymnastics ("for the correction of physcial defects"), marching ("to develop subjective controls"), dancing, swimming, archery, basketball, field hockey, tennis, track and field.
In 1930-31 women were offered a teaching minor, and some of the theory courses in Anatomy and Men's Physical Education opened enrollment to women students. In 1936-37 a joint degree program with the School of Education was established, with specialization in dance, physiotherapy, hygiene, or general sports. The following year a professional program offering the Ph.D. and Masters degrees was established.
Throughout the 1930's the faculty of the Department of Hygiene and Physical Education for Women was involved in research studies in anatomy and physiology. In 1939-40 a division of Physical Therapy was added to the department, offering both a Master of Arts, and a Ph.D. minor.
In 1940 the department's name was changed to the School of Health. 1942-43 brought the addition of a division of Nutrition and Dietetics, a nursery school program, and a special program on the treatmetit of poliomyelitis in the division of Physical Therapy.
The School of Health was dissolved in 1945-46. The physical education requirement for undergraduates was reduced from four years to two years.
The Men's and Women's Student Health Services were combined and located in one wing of the Roble Gymnasium, with the Palo Alto Medical Clinic assuming administrative responsibilities. The program in Nutrition and Dietetics was dropped. Physical Therapy became a fully separate department, operating in conjunction with the division of Physical Therapy of the Stanford Hospital. The Health Education courses, professional degrees programs, and their faculty were transferred to the School of Education. Degree programs leading to a Bachelor of Arts, a secondary teaching credential, and/or advanced degrees continued to be available to women until 1963. Thereafter, the education courses were open only to male students.
Following the departmental rearrangement in the mid-'40s only physical activity courses and extra-curricular activities remained under the administration of the new Women's Physical Education Department. The administrative organization of the department remained essentially unchanged until its merger in 1975 with the Department of Physical Education for Men to form the Department of Athletics, Physical Education, and Recreation.
Description of the Collection
Records of the department include staff meeting minutes, newsletters, correspondence, materials relating to medical research projects of the faculty, and records of the operation of the Women's Student Health Service. Also includes course materials, correspondence, reports, memoranda, photographs, and miscellaneous materials pertaining to the department and photographs and records of two dance clubs - the Stanford Hoedowners and the Stanford Folk Dancers. Of note are completed survey forms on the recreational needs of women college students, 1948, from Mills College, Stanford, University of New Mexico, and University of Wyoming, with related correspondence and notes.
Scope and Contents
EXPLANATIONS OF CERTAIN FOLDER TITLES
The folder titles in the general files are occasionally misleading. An explanation of the types of materials filed under particular headings follows:
"Daily Reports" "Daily Summary Reports" Contents include 'statistics on who used the Health Service and why. "Rest Home Reports"
"Examinations" "Houses -- Examinations and Contents include lists of students and schedules of physical examinations. Recommendations" "Orthopedics" "Sororities"
"Health Reports" Contents include records of student hospitilazations, testing of milk and water samples, reports on communicable diseases, state-wide polio statistics.
"Rest Assignment Reports" [Students unable to participate in Physical Education classes were assigned to "Rest."] Contents include reports on who was assigned rest, and why.
"University Health Service" Contents include reports on water and milk sample testing, examinations of food handlers, etc.
"Width-Height Tables" Contents include correspondence regarding a publication by the medical director on correlation of stature and weight.
DEFINITIONS OF ABBREVIATIONS USED
ASHA American Student Health Association
NAAF National Amateur Athletic Federation
WAA Women's Athletic Association
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged by accession.
Access Terms
Bunting, Helen Masters.; Guthrie, Luell W.; Henderson, Dorothy Heilman.; Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Stanford University. Department of Physical Hygiene.; Stanford University. Women's Physical Education Department.; Women's Student Health Service.; Photoprints.; Physical education for women.; Reprints.; Sports for women.
Collection Contents
- Records, 1928-1975
  The series is arranged in five subseries: 1. Women's P.E. staff minutes & newsletters, 1928-1975. 2. Women's P.E. Department - general files, 1920-1968. 3. Course materials, 1937-1970. 4. Memoranda, reports, 1919-1975. 5. Photographs, undated.
  - Women's P.E. staff minutes & newsletters, 1928-1975
    - 1928-29 through 1930-31 (Box 1)
    - 1937-38 through 1939-40 (Box 1)
    - 1940-41 through 1942-43 (Box 1)
    - 1943-44 through 1945-46 (Box 1)
    - 1946-47 through 1948-49 (Box 1)
    - 1949-50 through 1950-51 (Box 1)
    - 1952 through 1954 (Box 1)
    - 1955 through 1956 (Box 1)
    - 1955-56 through 1959-60 (Box 1)
    - 1960-61 through 1962-63 (Box 1)
    - 1963-64 through 1964-65 (Box 1)
    - 1965-66 through 1966-67 (Box 1)
    - 1967-68 through 1968-69 (Box 1)
    - 1969-70 through 1971-72 (Box 1)
    - 1972-73 through 1974-75 (Box 1)
  - Women's P.E. Department - general files, 1920-1968
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1920-1929 (Box 1)
    - A, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - B, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Budget, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Bunting, Miss Helen Masters, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - C, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Clippings, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Comptroller, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - D, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Dean of Women, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - E, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - F, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Forms and form letters, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - G, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - H, 1929-1930 (Box 1a)
    - I, 1929-1930 (Box 1a)
    - J, 1929-1930 (Box 1a)
    - K, 1929-1930 (Box 1a)
    - L, 1929-1930 (Box 1a)
    - Lists, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Lockers vs. Baskets, new gymnasium for women, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - M, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - Mc, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - N, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - New building, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - O, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - P, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - Pink slips, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - President, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - Q, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - R, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - Registrar, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - Roble Gymnasium & Pool, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - S, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - T, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - U, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - V, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - W, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - X, Y, Z, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - Late leaves, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
    - Applications and Recommendations, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - A, B, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - C, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Comptroller, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - D, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Dean of Women, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Director of Roble Gymnasium, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - E, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Examinations, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - F, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Fees, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Forms and form letters, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - G, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - H, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Health data and reports, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Houses -- examinations and recommendations, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - I, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - J, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - K, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - L, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Library, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - M, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Mc, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - N, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - New building, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - O, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - P, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - President, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Q, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - R, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Registrar, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
    - S, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
    - T, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
    - U, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
    - V, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
    - W, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
    - X, Y, Z, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
    - A, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - B, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Budget, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - C, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Comptroller, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - D, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Dean of Women, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Director of Roble Gymnasium, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - E, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Equipment, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Examinations, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - F, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Forms and form letters, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - G, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - H, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Health Reports, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Houses -- examinations and recomendations, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - I, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - J, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - K, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - L, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Library, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - M, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Mc, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - N, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - O, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - P, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - President, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Q, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - R, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - S, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - Staff, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - T, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - U, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - V, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - W, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - X, Y, Z, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
    - A, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - B, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - B, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Budget, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - C, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Comptroller, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - D (Box 3)
    - Dance Drama, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Dean of Women, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Director of Women's Gymnasium, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - E, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - F, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Forms and form letters, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - G, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - H, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Houses -- examinations and recommendations, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Health reports, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - I, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - J, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - K, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - L, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Library, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - M, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Mc, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Minutes -- staff meetings, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - N, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - O, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - P, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - President, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Q, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - R, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Registrar, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - S, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - T, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - U, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - V, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - W, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - X, Y, Z, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - A, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - American Physical Education Association, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - B, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Budget, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - C, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Comptroller, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - D, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Dance Drama, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Dean of Women, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - E, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Education Committee, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Equipment, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Examinations, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - F, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Forms and form letters, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - G, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - H, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Health reports, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - J, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - L, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Library, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - M, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Mc, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Medical Women's International Assoc. Congress, Stockholm, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Minutes -- staff meetings, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - N, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - O, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - President, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - R, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - Registrar, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - S, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - T, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - V, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - W, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - X, Y, Z, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - A, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - B, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Budget, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - C, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Comptroller, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - D, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Dance Drama, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Dean of Women, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - E, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Equipment, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Examinations, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - F, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Forms and form letters, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - G, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - H, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Health reports, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Henderson, Dr. Dorothy Heilman, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - I, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - J, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - K, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - L, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Library, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - M, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Mc, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Medical investigations, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Minutes of staff meetings, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - N, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - O, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - P, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Personal - Medical Adviser of Women, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - President, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - R, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Registrar, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - S, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - T, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - U, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - V, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - W, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - X, Y, Z, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Daily report - Autumn Quarter [visits to Women's Student Health Service], 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Daily report - Winter Quarter [visits to Women's Student Health Service], 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Daily report - Spring Quarter [visits to Women's Student Health Service], 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Daily report - Summer Quarter [visits to Women's Student Health Service], 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Daily summary report - Autumn [visits to Women's Student Health Service], 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Daily summary report- Winter [visits to Women's Student Health Service], 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Daily summary report - Spring [visits to Women's Student Health Service], 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Daily summary report - Summer [visits to Women's Student Health Service], 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Hospital reports, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - Rest Home reports, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    - President, 1935-1936 (Box 6)
    - Daily Summary Reports [Women's Health Service] Autmnn, 1935-1936 (Box 6)
    - A, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - B, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Budget, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - C, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Comptroller, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, Summer Quarter, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - D, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Dean of Women, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - E, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Equipment, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Examinations, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - F, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Forms and form letters, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - G, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - H, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Health reports, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - J, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - K, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - L, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Library, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - M, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Mc, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Minutes of staff meetings, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - N, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - News Notes, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - O, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Organization of department, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - P, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Personal [correspondence of medical director], 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - President, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - President's Report, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - R, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Registrar, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Rental of Women's Gymnasium, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Reprints, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - S, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Statistics, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Summer Recreation Program, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - T, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - U, V, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - W, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Width-weight tables, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Daily Report -- Autumn Quarter [visits to Women's Health Service], 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Daily Report -- Winter Quarter [visits to Women's Health Service], 1936-1937 (Box 6)
    - Daily Report -- Spring Quarter [visits to Women's Health Service], 1936-1937 (Box 7)
    - Daily Report -- Summer Quarter [visits to Women's Health Service], 1936-1937 (Box 7)
    - Daily Report -- Summer Quarter [visits to Women's Health Service], 1936-1937 (Box 7)
    - Hospital reports, 1936-1937 (Box 7)
    - Rest Home reports, 1936-1937 (Box 7)
    - A, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - American Student Health Association, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Announcement of courses, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - B, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - C, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Comptroller, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - D, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Dean of' Women, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - E, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Education, School of, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Equipment, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Examinations, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - F, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Forms and form letters, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - G, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - H, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Health reports, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - I, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - J, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - K, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - L, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Library, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - M, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Mc, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - N, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - P, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Personal, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
      Correspondence and research papers ofmedical director, 2 folders.
    - President, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - R, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Registrar, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Rental of Women's Gymnasium, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Reprints, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - S, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Statistics, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Statistics -- Health Service, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - T, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - University Health Service, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - V, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - W, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Width-weight tables, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Y.W.C.A, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - A, 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - American Student Health Association meeting, New York, 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - Announcement of courses, 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - B, 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - C, 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - Committee for Cooperation with Chinese Universities, 1938-1939 (Box 7)
    - Comptroller, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Conferences -- Summer Quarter, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - D, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Dean of Women, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Director's Conference, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Director's meeting -- reservations, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - E, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Education, School of, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Equipment, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Examinations, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - F, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Forms and form letters, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - G, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - H, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Health reports, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - I, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - J, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - K, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - L, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Library, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Mc, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - M, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Medical Advisor of Men, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Minutes of staff meeting, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - N, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - O, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - P, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Personal, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
      Correspondence, etc., of Medical Advisor.
    - Physical Education for Women, Dept. of, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - President, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Publications, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - R, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Registrar, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Rental of Women's Gymnasium, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Reprints, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Research Committee A.A.H.P.E.R., 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Ricker, -- Diets, etc., 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - S, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Schedule, Autumn, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Statistics, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Spectator Course, W101, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - T, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - University Health Service, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - V, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - W, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - Width-weight tables, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - X, Y, Z, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - YWCA, 1938-1939 (Box 8)
    - A, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
    - American Student Health Association meeting, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
    - Applications and recommendations, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
    - Appointments, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
    - B, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
    - Biological Abstracts, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
    - Budget -- Examination Fund, 1939-1940 (Box 8)